These networking levels from protostar are not really security related, but they are
这些来自 ProtoStar的网络级别问题，并不真正与安全相关，
great to do some first simple network programming.
但对一些简单的网络编程来说，他们真的很好。
And just for the sake of having a complete series from exploit-exercises, we will solve
为了有一个 exploit-exercises 完整的体现，
these challenges too.
我们也是会完成这些挑战。
&lt;intro&gt;
；
The previous two videos were already a good introduction into networking, sockets, TCP,
前两个视频已经很好地介绍了网络、套接字、TCP，
and, so let’s build on this foundation by writing a python script to interact with this
因此，让我们在此基础上，编写一个Python脚本，
program over the network.
借用该程序来与网络进行交互。
Especially for CTFs, this is an important part, because for many many challenges you
特别是对于CTF来说，这是一个重要的部分，因为对于许多挑战，
interact with a service over TCP.
你都是通过TCP，与服务(器)交互的。
So the exploit you write has to do this over the network.
所以，你写的漏洞脚本，必须在网络上完成。
Let’s have a look at this level.
让我们来看看这个级别问题。
I won’t go over the meaning of all these unknown functions, because we have done so
我不会再讨论所有这些未知函数的含义，
in episode hex 19.
因为我们已经在(hex 19 / 25)集，讲过了。
As we see in the defines, or simply by checking netstat on the VM, we can see that net level
正如，我们在定义中看到的，或者只检查了虚拟机上的 netstat，
1 is running on port 2998.
我们可以看到级别1网络，正在端口2998上运行。
Again we could use netcat to talk to this service, but this time, we want to write a
我们可以再次使用 netcat，与此服务进行对话，但这次，
python script.
我们要编写一个Python脚本。
But let’s first have a look at the run function.
但，我们先来看一下 run 函数。
First run generates a random unsigned integer, and then we sprintf the number into fub.
首先，运行生成一个随机的无符号整数，然后，我们将该数字 sprintf 到fub 中。
We haven’t seen S-printf before - so other than regular printf which writes the resulting
我们以前没有看到过 S-printf —— 与 printf 不同，
string to stdout, sprintf will write the resulting string the address specified in the first
它会把结果字符串，写入到 stdout，
argument - in this case buf.
sprintf将把结果字符串，写入由第一个参数指定的地址 —— 在本例中是 buf。
This means `fub` will contain the decimal representation of the number in ascii, and
“fub”的意思，将包含以 ASCII 表示的十进制数字，
not contain the raw byte values.
并且，不包含原始字节值。
Then write will write to the socket, thus sending us the integer number, thus the raw
然后，write 将写入套接字，从而向我们发送整数，
bytes.
还有原始字节。
That’s what we saw returned by netcat.
这就是我们看到的，netcat 返回的结果。
After that, the program will wait for user input with fread.
之后，程序用 fread，等待用户输入。
Once we send some data it will overwrite any newline or carriage return with a null byte.
一旦我们发送了一些数据，它将用一个空字节，覆盖任何换行符或回车符。
This makes sense because when we for example use netcat and hit ENTER to send something,
说得通，因为当我们使用netcat，并点击enter，发送信息时，
it will include a newline at the end, because that’s the key we pressed.
最后，会有一个换行符，因为这就是我们的按键。
But obviously this program only wants the characters we actually meant to send - thus
但是很明显，这个程序只需要我们实际发送的字符-
stripping away the newline.
因此剥去换行。
Then it compares the original number with the number it received and either prints success
然后，它将原始数字与接收到的数字进行比较，
or fail.
并打印成功或者失败。
So, lets start to write our python script.
所以，让我们开始编写Python脚本。
But how do we do that?
但我们该怎么做呢？
Maybe a first hint on how to do network programming could be to look at how netcat connects to
网络编程的第一个提示，可能是，
the server.
看 netcat 如何连接到服务器。
So we can use strace, to trace all syscalls of netcat.
所以，我们可以使用strace ，跟踪 netcat 的所有 syscall。
Now let’s try to identify the important ones, and then we try to figure out how to
现在，让我们试着找出重要的，然后，
implement them in python.
我们试着在 python 中实现它们。
First one is obviously the call to socket, so let’s look into the python socket documentation
第一个，显然是对 socket 的调用，所以，我们来看看，
on how to do that in or script.
python socket文档，关于如何实现这一点。
So the call to socket uses the parameters PF_INET and SOCK_STREAM and when we look here
所以，对 socket 的调用使用参数 PF_INET 和 SOCK_STREAM，
in the python doc we see something very similar.
现在，看着 python文档，发现一些非常相似的东西。
Except that it suggests to use AF_INET.
但，它建议使用 AF_INET 。
So I wondered what’s the difference between PF and AF_INET, so I googled and surprisingly,
所以，我想知道 PF 和 AF_INET 之间，有什么区别，所以我在谷歌上搜索并惊讶地发现，
it turns out, that that is a remnant of an idea that never took off, and in fact in the
事实证明，这是一个从未起飞的想法的残渣，
linux kernel it’s now simply defined as being the same as AF_INET.
在实际的 Linux内核中，它现在被简单定义为 AF_INET 。
Ha, learned something today.
哈，今天学到了一些东西。
And the python doc then uses connect to connect to a hostname, or an IP and port.
然后，python文档，使用 connect 连接到主机名或IP和端口。
Which we can also see in the strace.
我们也可以在 strace 看到。
Here it’s called with the port 2998 and the ip address 127.0.0.1
这里，用端口2998 和 IP地址127.0.0.1 调用
So we can also just use that.
所以，我们也可以用它。
Cool.
酷。
And now we can use send and receive with this socket.
现在，我们可以对这个套接字，发送和接收。
Obviously we want to read the number that is sent to us, so we use recv, but we have
显然，我们想读取发送给我们的数字，所以我们使用 recv，
to specify how much data we want to read.
但是我们必须指定，要读取的数据量。
In this case we expect an unsigned integer, which is 32bit large, thus we have to read
在这种情况下，我们需要一个32位大的，无符号整数，
4 bytes.
因此，我们必须读取4个字节(32位)。
Now let’s simply print the data we receive and then test it.
现在，让我们简单打印接收到的数据，然后测试它。
Cool.
酷。
Btw, also notice that when we request a new number very quickly, that a lot of numbers
顺便说一句，当我们快速请求一个新数字时，
are the same and not random?
也会注意到很多相同数字，不是随机的吗？
That’s because in the code the random number generator is seeded by the time in seconds.
这是因为在代码中，随机数生成器的种子，是以秒为单位的时间。
Thus if we send fast enough, the seconds will be the same and thus produce the same pseudo
因此，如果我们发送足够快，秒数将相同，
random number.
从而产生相同的伪随机数。
Don’t you ever use a non random source as a seed for a pseudo random number generator!
不要使用非随机源，作为伪随机数生成器的种子！
And now it’s easy to solve it, because we are already very experience with converting
现在，很容易解决，因为我们已经有了转换的经验，
numbers to raw bytes and raw bytes to numbers from all the exploits with memory values that
就是我们曾写过的漏洞脚本中，关于内存值方面的，
we have written.
原始字节和数字之间的相互转换。
So we can simply use the struct module and convert the raw binary data back to an unsigned
所以我们可以简单使用struct模块，将原始二进制数据转换回，
integer, and then send it as a string back to the server.
无符号的整数，然后将其作为字符串发送回服务器。
Remember that struct unpack returns a tuple, so the actual unpacked number is the first
记住 struct unpack 返回一个元组，因此，个
element.
实际的unpacked数是第一元素。
Mh… it seems to hang.
嗯… 好像挂起来了。
Let’s try it again.
让我们再试一次。
Now it seems to work.
现在它似乎起作用了。
The receive hangs when it is waiting for data and doesn’t get any, so I assume the server
接收在等待数据时挂起，没有任何数据，
sends too fast and there is no buffer buffering the data, and when we are finally ready to
因此我假设服务器发送太快，没有缓冲区缓冲数据，
recv data, the data is already lost in the void.
当我们终于准备好接收数据，数据已经在 void 丢失。
Anyhow, it worked.
不管怎样，它起作用了。
Doesn’t have to be perfect, as long as you succeed once, the attack was sucessful.
不必完美，只要你成功一次，攻击就成功了。
This episode is so short, and these challenges are not really about security anyway, so let’s
这一集太短了，不管怎样，这些挑战并不是真正的安全问题，
quickly solve the next one too.
所以让我们，快速解决下一个问题。
Net2 is very similar, we again have a network setup with a program listening on port 2997.
net2非常相似，我们再次设置了一个网络，在端口2997上，监听一个程序。
In the run function we see a for loop that runs 4 times and each time it generates a
在 run 函数中，我们看到一个for循环，它运行4次，每次生成一个随机数，
random number, adds it to the sum of them all and then sends it over the network.
将其添加到所有数字的总和中，然后通过网络发送。
The description also says that we have to add 4 32bit integers.
（挑战）描述，还指出我们必须添加4个32位整数。
And it already warns us about the possibility of it wrapping.
它已经警告我们，wrapping包装的可能性。
Or in proper terms, it warns us about an integers overflow - which again is security relevant.
或者用恰当的术语，它警告我们整数会溢出 —— 这也是安全相关的。
Ok, so let’s copy our previous script and quickly modify it to read 4 integers and then
好的，那么我们复制前面的脚本，并快速修改为读取4个整数，
calculate the sum.
然后计算总和。
We can simply extend the struct unpack modifier, and then we can also just create a sum over
我们可以简单扩展 struct unpack 修饰符，
the resulting tuple.
然后还可以在结果元组之上，创建一个 sum。
Easy as that.
很容易。
The code expects the result not in an ascii decimal representation but as a raw binary,
代码期望的结果，不是ASCII十进制表示的，而是一个原始二进制，
so we can use struct pack to covnert it to a binary string and send that.
所以，我们可以使用struct pack，将其转换为二进制字符串并发送它。
Oh.
哦。
haha.
哈哈。
I wanted to show that this doesn’t work.
我想证明，这不管用。
because of the integer overflow.
因为整数溢出。
If we have a look at the result of the sum in binary we can see that it contains more
如果我们看一下二进制总和的结果，我们会发现它，
than 32bits, and that cannot be.
包含超过32位，而这不应该啊。
An integer is only 32bit large.
而一个整数应该只有32位大。
So what happens is, that the integer is simply overflowing, or wrapping around.
所以发生的是，整数只是溢出，或者包漏了。
This means the carry of the highest bit is just lost.
这意味着，最高位的进位刚刚丢失。
Well, it’s not entirely true, the CPU is actually aware of this, when an arithmetic
嗯，这并不完全正确，CPU实际上，意识到了这一点，当一个算法，
operation such as an addition ends up overflowing the value in a register, a special overflow
诸如加法之类的操作，若在寄存器中，最后溢出了值，
flag is set that could be checked.
会设置一个特殊的溢出标志，这可以用来检查。
But anyway, in this case our unsigned integer on the server will always wrap around.
但无论如何，在这种情况下，服务器上的无符号整数，将始终溢出。
And apparently this old python struct version actually did that for us, but this behaviour
显然，这个旧的python struct 版本，确实为我们做了这些，
got deprecated.
但是这个行为被贬低了。
So we can simply do the same in our code.
所以，我们可以在代码中做同样的事情。
As I said, this issue is called integer overflow, and when you search for this you will find
如我所说，这个问题叫做整数溢出，当你搜索这个问题时，
many bug reports about it.
你会发现很多关于它的错误报告。
Let’s make a simple example of a typical integer overflow issue.
让我们做一个典型整数溢出问题的简单示例。
Let’s say you have a loop that keeps reading data and adds the size to an overall size
假设您有一个循环，它不断读取数据，
variable.
并将大小添加到总大小的变量。
Once it’s done with the loop, it will know for how much data it has to allocate space
一旦完成了循环，它就会知道需要分配多少内存空间。
for.
为了。
The issue is now, if you manage to send so much data, that the counter overflows, wraps
现在的问题是，如果您打算发送这么多的数据，计数器却溢出，
around, a smaller space is allocated for the huge amounts of data, and then you have a
大量数据只分配一个较小的空间，
typical overflow condition.
这就是，典型溢出情况。
We are slowly heading into the final levels of exploit-exercises protostar and we start
我们正缓慢进入最后一级的 exploit-exercises protostar，
to see a little bit more intricate challenges.
我们开始看到一些更复杂的挑战。
So let’s stay focused and tackle these next!
所以，让我们集中注意力，解决下一个问题！